STEVEN DAWSON

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

A newly qualified Full Stack Developer bringing skills and competency in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, Django, Bootstrap, Git, Postgres and SQL, as well as with libraries such as Django, Flask, React, Bootstrap and Materialize, complimented with having had a successful 16-year career as a Teacher of PE and Maths. Demonstrates diverse life and technical experience on projects, with the ability to get things built and working across the stack. Consistently ensures that projects are delivered in line with scope, schedule, risks, outcomes, prioritisation, value and benefits. I am aiming for a role as a Software Developer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Codebase Development, Freelance Developer (own company), APR 2022 – PRESENT

- Setup as a Freelancer undertaking development work for clients including a health and lifestyle companies called CJA Balance and CJA Lifestyle, with the main activities including, admin manager, customer relations, patient onboarding and education, gocarless, stripe, zoho systems integrations and, automating processes.
- Utilised HTML, CSS, Python and Django to build a website for a company called Alvis Energy Solutions.
- Gathered project requirements and ensured these were accepted and approved by clients.
- Aligned activities to established business processes, protocols and quality standards, including conducting code reviews and proposing enhancements and improvements.

Code Institute, Student, MAY 2021 – MAY 2022

- Successfully completed a Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp, working with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and Python along with Flask and Django.
- Completed several projects including:

Projects:

 Lake District Tykes Cycling: Website developed using HTML and CSS, to provide a list of cycling routes for families with children that are beginners to families with children that are advanced cyclists and end fun, safe cycling routes that meet their needs. GitHub link

CONTACT DETAILS

Address: 44 Wolsey Close, Thornton-Cleveleys, FY5 2NZ

M: 07951069914

E: fullstacksteve18@gmail.com

LinkedIn GitHub Portfolio

TECHNICAL SKILLS OVERVIEW

- HTML 5
- MySQL
- Bootstrap
- Git
- Balsamiq
- CSS
- Postgres
- JQuery
- GitHub
- JavaScript
- Django
- Python
- Flask
- Materialize
- React

EDUCATION

2021 to 2022: Code Institute

Full Stack Web Development Diploma

2002 to 2005: St Martins College, Lancaster, BA (Hons) in Physical Education with QTS (Secondary)

2000 to 2002: Blackpool Sixth Form College, A Levels in Physical Education, Biology A-S Levels in Sociology, Graphics

1999 to 2000: Rossall School (Rugby Scholarship), Attained Mathematics GCSE Grade C

Awarded 'Player of the Year' for Rugby

STEVEN DAWSON

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Rock Paper Scissors Lizard Spock: Website that offers users an interactive gaming experience and is an adaptation of the popular game of Rock Paper Scissors. Created using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. GitHub link
- Ultimate Hangman: A game that provides the user with three optional categories to choose from and depending on their choice, the words will be related to that category. Created using Python.
 GitHub link
- Cockapoo Cafe: Allows the user to interact with the cafe online by being greeted with a vibrant and welcoming page which portrays the purpose of the site. Created using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, Python, Django, Bootstrap and Postgres. GitHub link
- American Ale House: A website that provides the user the ability to purchase American brewed beers in the UK. Created using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, Python, Django, Bootstrap and Postgres. GitHub link

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Garstang Community Academy, Maths Teacher & PE Teacher, 2020 – 2021

- Delivered a high standard of Maths and PE teaching to pupils.
- Planned tutoring/teaching sessions and created/implemented key schemes of work to ensure the delivery of robust teaching.

West Craven High School, Maths Teacher & PE Teacher, Head of Faculty, 2005 - 2020

- Followed lesson plans/tutor guides and followed schedules to ensure that learners complete within agreed deadlines.
- Created a stimulating, creative and enjoyable learning environment, whilst ensuring that resources were ready and available for learners.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Hobbies include taking part in Hackathons, keeping fit, played Rugby Union since the age of 7, represented Lancashire, captain of the University team

REFERENCES

On request